So variables, data types, what makes
them tick? So we're going to talk about
that today. A variable, when you create
a variable, all you're doing is you're
saying, "Hey, computer, there's a piece
of information I need you to keep track
of." And then you're going to say,
"Please store this piece of
information." Different pieces of
information take up different sizes and
different amounts of memory. And so
those are called data types. When you
store something on your computer, it
needs somewhere to store it. So, what it
does is it takes all of the memory it
has available and then it allocates a
small section of that memory and says,
"Okay, here's where I'm going to store
the information that you give me." And
it can store it in different size boxes.
So, I've got a box this size
and I've got a box this size. Your
computer does a similar thing when it's
storing pieces of information. It tries
to find the right size box to store it
in. So, if
I had a small piece of information, I'd
store it in this box. If I had a larger
piece of information, I'd store it in
this box. And that is how your computer
works with pieces of information because
it finds the right box for them.
Now, if I were to ask you what is in
this box, you probably couldn't tell me.
Not unless you've watched further in
this video and you know exactly what's
in this box. If I put a label on this
box and it said electronics, then you'd
probably guess that there's electronics
in here. If I put a different label on
this box and I said action figures, then
you guess they're probably action
figures. I could be really specific with
the label and I could say this box um if
I put a label on it that said poseable
action figures, then you'd probably
guess that there are some pososeable
action figures in there. As a matter of
fact,
there are. So, I have poseable action
figures. And then this can illustrate
the point of size. So this box, this
box, different sizes. If I took the
action figure from the one box and
attempted to store it in the other box,
it probably doesn't fit very well. And
so because it does not fit, um, if I was
a computer, then I would throw a fit and
you would get an error. So when you are
programming with variables,
what you are saying is you're saying set
aside a certain amount of space. Some
variables take up more space than
others. And we'll talk a little bit
about that in another video. But I want
you to think when you're creating a
variable, how much space do you want it
to take up? Do you want to take up a
little bit of space or a lot of space?
And then when you're naming your
variable, that's like putting a label on
these boxes. Do you want your variable
to be descriptive so that someone knows
what's inside of it or do you just want
to put a random label on it and then no
one will know what's in there? So, those
are some things to think about with
variables. We'll talk about the actual
code in the next video.